<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<page>
  <title><![CDATA[What's New in VisIt]]></title>
  <IM>LLNL-WEB-667075</IM>
  <owner><![CDATA[Page Owner Name]]></owner>
  <lastchanged><![CDATA[February 25, 2015]]></lastchanged>
  <template><![CDATA[l2]]></template> 
  <content>
    <![CDATA[
	
<link rel="stylesheet" href="content/css/mods.css" media="screen" />	

<div class="row">	
<div class="span9">

<ul class="nav nav-tabs">
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit">VisIt Home</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/downloads">Downloads</a></li>
  	<li class="active"><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/new">What's New</a></li>
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/screenshots">Screen Shots</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/gallery">Gallery</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/faqs">FAQs</a></li>
</ul>

<h2>February, 2015 - VisIt 2.9 released</h2>
<p>VisIt is a distributed, parallel visualization and graphical analysis tool for data defined on two- and three-dimensional (2D and 3D) meshes. Version 2.9, which can be <a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/downloads">downloaded from this site</a>, contains many bug-fixes and new features. For a complete list of changes see the <a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/releases/release-notes-2.9.0">VisIt 2.9 Release Notes</a>.</p>
<h4>1.  VisIt was ported to the BlueGene/Q platform.</h4>
<p>The <i>build_visit_BGQ</i> script can be used to build a statically linked version of VisIt's server components for use on BlueGene/Q.</p>
<h4>2.  A number of enhancements were made to Libsim to better support batch oriented in situ visualization.</h4>
<ul>
<li>Libsim was enhanced so it provides a <i>VisItRestoreSession()</i> function which can be used to set up visualizations for a simulation that is run in batch mode. VisIt can be run normally to connect interactively to the simulation to set up plots and save a session file. The session file that gets created can be used to set up plots for subsequent batch-only simulation runs. Once plots have been set up via <i>VisItRestoreSession()</i>, the <i>VisItSaveWindow()</i> function can be used to save images.</li>
<li>Libsim was enhanced so it provides a <i>VisItExportDatabase()</i> function which can be used to export the active plots in a simulation that is run in batch mode. This function enables users to automatically export processed geometry from libsim.</li>
</ul>
<h4>3.  VisIt was integrated with <a href="https://www.seedme.org/">SeedMe.org</a>.</h4>
<p>It is now possible to easily share your visualizations results via the SeedMe python module, which is now included in VisIt's CLI. See the <a href="http://visitusers.org/index.php?title=Seedme">Seedme examples wiki page</a> on visitusers.org, the <a href="https://www.seedme.org/documentation/programmatic-python-usage"> SeedMe programatic guide</a> and the <a href="https://www.seedme.org/cli-guide">SeedMe command line guide</a> for examples.</p>

[Go to <a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/releases">Archive of Releases</a>]

</div>
</div>	
	  
	  ]]>
  </content>
</page>
