<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<page>
  <title><![CDATA[What's New in VisIt]]></title>
  <IM>LLNL-WEB-717999</IM>
  <owner><![CDATA[Page Owner Name]]></owner>
  <lastchanged><![CDATA[January 18, 2017]]></lastchanged>
  <template><![CDATA[l2]]></template> 
  <content>
    <![CDATA[
	
<link rel="stylesheet" href="content/css/mods.css" media="screen" />	

<div class="row">	
<div class="span9">

<ul class="nav nav-tabs">
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit">VisIt Home</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/downloads">Downloads</a></li>
  	<li class="active"><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/new">What's New</a></li>
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/screenshots">Screen Shots</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/gallery">Gallery</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/faqs">FAQs</a></li>
</ul>

<h2>January, 2017 - VisIt 2.12.1 released</h2>
<p>VisIt is a distributed, parallel visualization and graphical analysis tool for data defined on two- and three-dimensional (2D and 3D) meshes. Version 2.12.1 is primarily a bug-fix release that resolves about ten important issues. For a complete list of changes see the <a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/releases/release-notes-2.12.1">VisIt 2.12.1 Release Notes</a>.</p>
<h2>November, 2016 - VisIt 2.12 released</h2>
<p>VisIt 2.12 contains many bug-fixes and new features. It is closer to a bug fix release in scope except for the fact that the component protocols changed, necessitating a major release. For a complete list of changes see the <a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/releases/release-notes-2.12.0">VisIt 2.12 Release Notes</a>.</p>
<h2>August, 2016 - VisIt 2.11 released</h2>
<p>VisIt 2.11 contains many bug-fixes and new features. For a complete list of changes see the <a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/releases/release-notes-2.11.0">VisIt 2.11 Release Notes</a>.</p>
<h4>1.  The re-architecting of the Parallel Integral Curve System was completed.</h4>
<p>The re-architecting of the Parallel Integral Curve System (PICS), which formed the basis for functionality such as the Streamline and Poincare plots, has been completed. The changes began with the 2.9 release and provide a more flexible system with increased functionality. The most recent change in 2.11 is the removal of the Streamline plot. The same functionalty can now be achieved using the IntegralCurve operator and the Pseudocolor plot. The new system consists of four operators that feed their results into the Pseudocolor plot for display. The operators include the IntegralCurve, LCS (Lagrangian Coherent Structures), LimitCycle and Poincare operators. The Pseudocolor plot has been enhanced to be allow it to render lines in the same manner as the Streamline plot. For example, the Pseudocolor plot can now display lines as tubes and add spheres to the ends of the lines to show seed points. The Streamline Info query has been replaced with the Integral Curve Info query. For more information on using these operators, see the <a href="http://www.visitusers.org/index.php?title=Parallel_Integral_Curve_System_in_VisIt">Parallel Integral Curve System in VisIt</a> on the visitusers.org wiki.</p>
<h4>2.  Advanced movie making capabilities have been added.</h4>
<p>The qplot and visit_flow Python modules are now included as part of the standard VisIt distribution. The qplot module contains plotting routines based on Qt. The visit_flow module contains a dataflow infrastructure for compositing and annotating images. Together these two modules allow users to create sophisticated movies using VisIt. See the <a href="http://visitusers.org/index.php?title=Visit-tutorial-Advanced-movie-making">Advanced movie making</a> tutorial on the visitusers.org wiki for a detailed tutorial on using these modules to create a movie.</p>
<h4>3.  New color tables have been added.</h4>
<ul>
<li>The <i>inferno</i>, <i>plasma</i>, <i>magma</i> and <i>viridis</i> color tables from matplotlib were added to VisIt. These color tables were developed to be perceptually uniform and more friendly to color blindness. For more details see <a href="https://bids.github.io/colormap/">https://bids.github.io/colormap/</a>. These  color tables are available under the <a href="https://creativecommons.org/about/cc0">CCO license</a>. Thanks to Akshay Subramaniam of Standford for providing the ct formated variants of these tables.</li>
  <li>The <i>viridis_light</i> color table, contributed by Robert Blake of LLNL, formally at John's Hopkins, was added to VisIt. Low saturation on the lower end of viridis can make it hard to use in 3D settings where lighting is applied. This variant helps address this.</li>
</ul>

[Go to <a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/releases">Archive of Releases</a>]

</div>
</div>	
	  
	  ]]>
  </content>
</page>
