<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<page>
  <title><![CDATA[What's New in VisIt]]></title>
  <IM>LLNL-WEB-659427</IM>
  <owner><![CDATA[Page Owner Name]]></owner>
  <lastchanged><![CDATA[October 13, 2014]]></lastchanged>
  <template><![CDATA[l2]]></template> 
  <content>
    <![CDATA[
	
<link rel="stylesheet" href="content/css/mods.css" media="screen" />	

<div class="row">	
<div class="span9">

<ul class="nav nav-tabs">
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit">VisIt Home</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/downloads">Downloads</a></li>
  	<li class="active"><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/new">What's New</a></li>
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/screenshots">Screen Shots</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/gallery">Gallery</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/faqs">FAQs</a></li>
</ul>

<h2>October, 2014 - VisIt 2.8.1 released</h2>
<p>VisIt is a distributed, parallel visualization and graphical analysis tool for data defined on two- and three-dimensional (2D and 3D) meshes. Version 2.8.1, which can be <a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/downloads">downloaded from this site</a>, is primarily a bug-fix release that resolves about a dozen important issues. For a complete list of changes see the <a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/releases/release-notes-2.8.1">VisIt 2.8.1 Release Notes</a>.</p>
<h2>September, 2014 - VisIt 2.8 released</h2>
<p>VisIt 2.8 contains many bug-fixes and new features. For a complete list of changes see the <a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/releases/release-notes-2.8.0">VisIt 2.8 Release Notes</a>.</p>
<h4>1.  Many enhancements have been made to the database readers.</h4>
<ul>
<li>A reader for parallel Velodyne files was added.</li>
<li>A reader for ViSUS IDX files was added, incorporating view-dependent data loading.</li>
<li>A reader for MFEM files was added.</li>
<li>The Silo reader was updated to Silo 4.10.</li>
<li>The CGNS reader was updated to use cgnslib version 3.2.1.</li>
<li>The Curv2d reader can now read double-precision sized data.</li>
</ul>
<h4>2.  VisIt's export mechanism has been enhanced.</h4>
<ul>
<li>VisIt now exports all the active plots instead of just the first active plot, creating numbered files with one file per plot.</li>
<li>It is now possible to export all the time states in a dataset at once.</li>
</ul>
<h4>3.  The tabs in the Psueudocolor plot attributes window have been replaced with collapsible panels.</h4>
<p>This is an experimental change and we would like to hear user feedback on the usefulness of the feature before adding it to other windows.</p>

[Go to <a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/releases">Archive of Releases</a>]

</div>
</div>	
	  
	  ]]>
  </content>
</page>
