<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<page>
  <title><![CDATA[What's New in VisIt]]></title>
  <IM>LLNL-WEB-748158</IM>
  <owner><![CDATA[Page Owner Name]]></owner>
  <lastchanged><![CDATA[March 26, 2018]]></lastchanged>
  <template><![CDATA[l2]]></template> 
  <content>
    <![CDATA[
	
<link rel="stylesheet" href="content/css/mods.css" media="screen" />	

<div class="row">	
<div class="span9">

<ul class="nav nav-tabs">
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit">VisIt Home</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/downloads">Downloads</a></li>
  	<li class="active"><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/new">What's New</a></li>
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/screenshots">Screen Shots</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/gallery">Gallery</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/faqs">FAQs</a></li>
</ul>

<h2>March, 2018 - VisIt 2.13.1 released</h2>
<p>VisIt is a distributed, parallel visualization and graphical analysis tool for data defined on two- and three-dimensional (2D and 3D) meshes. Version 2.13.1 contains almost three dozen bug-fixes. For a complete list of changes see the <a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/releases/release-notes-2.13.1">VisIt 2.13.1 Release Notes</a>.</p>
<h2>October, 2017 - VisIt 2.13 released</h2>
<p>VisIt 2.13 contains many bug-fixes and new features. For a complete list of changes see the <a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/releases/release-notes-2.13.0">VisIt 2.13 Release Notes</a>.</p>
<h4>1.  VisIt now supports OpenSWR for rendering.</h4>
<p>You can now use build_visit to build a version of VisIt that supports using OpenSWR for software rendering. OpenSWR is an Intel software renderer that is now part of Mesa.</p>
<h4>2.  Added an SPCTH reader.</h4>
<p>VisIt now supports reading files in the SPCTH file format. SPCTH is the file format used by CTH, a popular simulation code developed by the Sandia National Laboratory.</p>
<h4>3.  Many enhancements and bug fixes have been made to the pick and query features.</h4>
<ul>
<li>Improved the accuracy and performance of picking on lines/line meshes in 3D.</li>
<li>Corrected many pick bugs.</li>
<li>Changed the default for Queries that operate on either <i>Original</i> or <i>Actual</i> data from <i>Original</i> to <i>Actual</i>. This makes them consistent with all the other queries that only operate on <i>Actual</i> data.</li>
</ul>

[Go to <a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/releases">Archive of Releases</a>]

</div>
</div>	
	  
	  ]]>
  </content>
</page>
