<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<page>
  <title><![CDATA[VisIt FAQs]]></title>
  <owner><![CDATA[Page Owner Name]]></owner>
  <lastchanged><![CDATA[March 21, 2013]]></lastchanged>
  <template><![CDATA[l2]]></template> 
  <content>
    <![CDATA[
	
<link rel="stylesheet" href="content/css/mods.css" media="screen" />	

<div class="row">	
<div class="span9">

<ul class="nav nav-tabs">
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit">VisIt Home</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/downloads">Downloads</a></li>
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/new">What's New</a></li>
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/screenshots">Screen Shots</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/gallery">Gallery</a></li>
	<li class="active"><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/faqs">FAQs</a></li>
</ul>

<h2>1. Who do I contact if I need help with VisIt?</h2>
<p> If you need help using VisIt or have questions about VisIt, send e-mail to one of the VisIt mailing lists. There are two open mailing lists open to anyone and three closed mailing lists for users associated with an organization that funds VisIt.</p>
<p>The two open mailing lists are:</p>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="mailto:visit-users@ornl.gov">visit-users@ornl.gov</a> </li>
  <li> <a href="mailto:visit-developers@ornl.gov">visit-developers@ornl.gov</a> </li>
</ul>
<p>The first mailing list is a venue for discussion among the VisIt community at large and is for users to ask questions and post suggestions about various aspects of VisIt, in topics anywhere from getting the code running to saving movies. The second mailing list is a venue for discussion among the VisIt developer community and is for developers to ask questions and post suggestions about various aspects of VisIt, including build issues, writing plugins, and any other aspects of VisIt development. You must subscribe to these lists before you can send and receive e-mail from them. Go to the <a href="https://elist.ornl.gov/mailman/listinfo/visit-users">visit-users list page</a> to subscribe to the user list and go to <a href="https://elist.ornl.gov/mailman/listinfo/visit-developers">visit-developers list page</a> to subscribe to the developers list.  If you can't access these web pages, you can subscribe by sending a blank email to <a href="mailto:visit-users-subscribe@elist.ornl.gov">visit-users-subscribe@elist.ornl.gov</a> or  <a href="mailto:visit-developers-subscribe@elist.ornl.gov">visit-developers-subscribe@elist.ornl.gov</a>, respectively.</p>
<p>If you are associated with SciDAC, GNEP or ASC, then you should send your questions to the appropriate closed mailing list:</p>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="mailto:visit-help-scidac@ornl.gov">visit-help-scidac@ornl.gov</a> </li>
  <li> <a href="mailto:visit-help-gnep@ornl.gov">visit-help-gnep@ornl.gov</a> </li>
  <li> <a href="mailto:visit-help-asc@ornl.gov">visit-help-asc@ornl.gov</a> </li>
</ul>

</div>
</div>	
	  
	  ]]>
  </content>
</page>
