<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<page>
  <title><![CDATA[VisIt FAQs]]></title>
  <owner><![CDATA[Page Owner Name]]></owner>
  <lastchanged><![CDATA[March 21, 2013]]></lastchanged>
  <template><![CDATA[l2]]></template> 
  <content>
    <![CDATA[
	
<link rel="stylesheet" href="content/css/mods.css" media="screen" />	

<div class="row">	
<div class="span9">

<ul class="nav nav-tabs">
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit">VisIt Home</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/downloads">Downloads</a></li>
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/new">What's New</a></li>
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/screenshots">Screen Shots</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/gallery">Gallery</a></li>
	<li class="active"><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/faqs">FAQs</a></li>
</ul>

<h2>12. What data file formats can VisIt read?</h2>
<p> VisIt can read several dozen file formats. The table below lists some of the most popular data file formats that VisIt can currently read in and visualize. For a complete list of supported file formats, at the time of the last documentation revision, look in the <a href="https://wci.llnl.gov/codes/visit/1.5/VisItUsersManual1.5.pdf">VisIt User's Manual</a>. You can also look at the <a href="new.html">What's New page</a> for more supported file formats. Finally, the <a href="http://www.visitusers.org/index.php?title=File_formats">File formats table at visitusers.org</a> is another good resource. Each file format is read in by a database reader plug-in that is distributed with VisIt. If you want to use VisIt with your data, you can write your data to a file format that VisIt already understands or you can write your own database reader plug-in. You can find out more about writing compatible files and writing a database reader plug-in in the <a href="https://wci.llnl.gov/codes/visit/2.0.0/GettingDataIntoVisIt2.0.0.pdf" title="GDIV" target="_blank">Getting Data Into VisIt</a> manual. </p>
<table class="table table-striped" border="0" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="1">
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <th>File Format</th>
      <th>Description</th>
      <th>URL</th>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>ANALYZE</td>
      <td>Format that stores fMRI data of brain scans. </td>
      <td><a href="http://www.mayo.edu/bir/PDF/ANALYZE75.pdf">ANALYZE file format description</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>ANSYS</td>
      <td>ASCII file format used for input to the ANSYS suite.</td>
      <td><a href="http://www.ansys.com">ANSYS home page</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>BOV (brick of values)</td>
      <td>BOV data are stored in two files. The first file is binary and it contains all of the data for an implied rectilinear grid stored as a brick of floats, doubles, etc. The second file is an ASCII header file that indicates the size of the data in the brick file as well as other attributes such as whether the brick is compressed. The contents of the ASCII header are described in the <a href="https://wci.llnl.gov/codes/visit/2.0.0/GettingDataIntoVisIt2.0.0.pdf" title="GDIV" target="_blank">Getting Data Into VisIt</a> manual.</td>
      <td>&nbsp;</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Boxlib</td>
      <td>File format used by the Boxlib library, an adaptive mesh refinement (AMR) framework. VisIt reads both 2D and 3D versions of the data file format.</td>
      <td><a href="http://www.c3.lanl.gov/%7Epernice/boxlib_2.5/boxlib/index.html">View Boxlib documentation</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>CGNS</td>
      <td>The CFD General Notation System (CGNS) consists of a collection of conventions, and software implementing those conventions, for the storage and retrieval of CFD (computational fluid dynamics) data. </td>
      <td><p><a href="http://www.cgns.org">CGNS home page </a></p>
          <p><a href="http://www.grc.nasa.gov/WWW/cgns/user/userguide.pdf">Download CGNS User's Guide</a></p></td>
    </tr>
	<tr>
      <td>Chombo</td>
      <td>This database reader plugin reads files from the Chombo package, which provides a set of tools for implementing finite difference methods for the solution of partial differential equations on block-structured adaptively refined rectangular grids.</td>
      <td><a href="http://seesar.lbl.gov/anag/chombo/" target="_blank">Chombo home page</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>CTRL</td>
      <td>CTRL files are the control files for TB-LMTO software, which uses the linear muffin-tin orbital (LMTO) method.</td>
      <td><a href="http://www.fkf.mpg.de/andersen/LMTODOC/LMTODOC.html" title="TB-LMTO-ASA program" target="_blank">STUTTGART TB-LMTO program</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Curve2D</td>
      <td>ASCII text file format containing pairs of x,y floating point values on each line. This file format is convenient for importing curve plots into VisIt. The curve format can store more than one curve provided you supply a variable name as a comment, beginning with &quot;#&quot;. </td>
      <td>&nbsp;</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Ensight Gold</td>
      <td>Proprietary file format for 2D and 3D data.</td>
      <td>File format described in chapter 2 of the <a href="http://www.ceintl.com/ensight76docs/Manuals/UserManual.pdf">Ensight User Manual</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Enzo</td>
      <td>Enzo is an adaptive mesh refinement (AMR), grid-based hybrid code (hydro + N-Body) which is designed to do simulations of cosmological structure formation.</td>
      <td><a href="http://cosmos.ucsd.edu/enzo/">Enzo home page</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Exodus</td>
      <td>Sandia National Laboratory's file format for storing data</td>
      <td><a href="http://endo.sandia.gov/SEACAS/Documentation/exodusII.pdf">Exodus II documentation</a></td>
    </tr>
	<tr>
      <td>FITS</td>
      <td>FITS stands for `Flexible Image Transport System' and is the standard astronomical data format endorsed by both NASA and the IAU. FITS is much more than an image format (such as JPG or GIF) and is primarily designed to store scientific data sets consisting of multi-dimensional arrays (1-D spectra, 2-D images or 3-D data cubes) and 2-dimensional tables containing rows and columns of data. </td>
      <td><a href="http://heasarc.gsfc.nasa.gov/docs/heasarc/fits.html" title="FITS home page" target="_blank">FITS home page </a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>FLASH</td>
      <td>ASC / Alliances Center for Astrophysical Thermonuclear Flashes</td>
      <td><a href="http://flash.uchicago.edu/website/home/" title="FLASH home page" target="_blank">FLASH home page </a></td>
    </tr>
	<tr>
      <td>FLUENT</td>
      <td>FLUENT is a very popular commercial CFD code. </td>
      <td><a href="http://www.fluent.com/software/fluent/index.htm" title="FLUENT home page" target="_blank">FLUENT home page </a></td>
    </tr>
	<tr>
      <td>FVCOM</td>
      <td>An unstructured grid, finite-volume, three-dimensional (3D) primitive equations ocean model that has been developed for the study of coastal oceanic and estuarine circulation.</td>
      <td><a href="http://fvcom.smast.umassd.edu/" title="FVCOM home page" target="_blank">FVCOM home page </a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>GGCM</td>
      <td>The centerpiece of the NSF/GEM, program is the development of a Geospace General Circulation Model (GGCM), to be used as a research tool as well as a prototype for space weather forecasting models. </td>
      <td><a href="http://openggcm.sr.unh.edu/wiki/index.php/Main_Page" title="Open GGCM home page" target="_blank">Open Geospace General Circulation Model</a></td>
    </tr>
	<tr>
      <td>GIS</td>
      <td>VisIt can read in several popular Geographic Information System (GIS) file formats using the <a href="http://www.gdal.org">GDAL library</a>. The content stored in GIS file formats varies widely but can include elevation maps, census data, vector data such as roads and streams, etc. Some of the supported file formats are DEM, ArcGrid, ESRI Shapefile. </td>
      <td><p><a href="http://www.gdal.org">GDAL home page</a></p>
          <p><a href="http://www.esri.com/library/whitepapers/pdfs/shapefile.pdf">ESRI Shapefile format description</a></p></td>
    </tr>
	<tr>
      <td>H5Nimrod</td>
      <td>The H5Nimrod plugin was developed at <a href="http://www.lbl.gov/" title="LBL" target="_blank">Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</a> to read Nimrod's HDF5 output file format. </td>
      <td><a href="http://www-vis.lbl.gov/Vignettes/NIMROD_TXCORP/index.html" title="H5Nimrod" target="_blank">H5Nimrod plugin information</a></td>
    </tr>
	<tr>
      <td>H5Part</td>
      <td>The H5Part plugin was developed at <a href="http://www.lbl.gov/" title="LBL" target="_blank">Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</a> to read  HDF5 part files. </td>
      <td><a href="http://www-vis.lbl.gov/Research/AcceleratorSAPP/H5PartVisIt.html" title="H5Part" target="_blank">H5Part plugin information</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Image</td>
      <td>VisIt can read in many image file formats created by popular image editing software including: BMP, JPEG, PNG, PPM, PNM, RGB, TIFF. Stacks of images can also be assembled into 3D volumes using a <em>.imgvol</em> file, which is a text file containing the names of the files to assemble into the 3D volume.</td>
      <td>&nbsp;</td>
    </tr>
		<tr>
      <td>ITAPS</td>
      <td>VisIt's ITAPS reader is one implementation
of the <a href="http://www.tstt-scidac.org/" title="TSTT" target="_blank">TSTT interface</a>  for representing mesh
and geometric data. The interface is experimental and is being actively
developed and refined by a follow-on SciDAC project called ITAPS
(Interoperable Technologies for Advanced Petascale Simulations). The interface
is designed to be used 'in-situ' and so there is no well defined, persistent
file format. VisIt's ITAPS reader is currently designed around the
<a href="http://cubit.sandia.gov/MOAB/" title="MOAB" target="_blank">MOAB implementation</a> of the TSTT interface.
Presently, it reads unstructured, single-block meshes consisting of any
combination of the finite element zoo of element types along with zone-
and node-centered fields implemented as TSTT 'tags'.</td>
      <td><a href="http://www.tstt-scidac.org/" title="TSTT" target="_blank">ITAPS</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>MFIX</td>
      <td>MFIX (<B>M</B>ultiphase <B>F</B>low with <B>I</B>nterphase e<B>X</B>changes) is a general-purpose computer code developed at the <a href="http://www.netl.doe.gov/" title="NETL" target="_blank">National Energy Technology Laboratory</a> (NETL) for describing the hydrodynamics, heat transfer and chemical reactions in fluid-solids systems.</td>
      <td><a href="http://www.mfix.org/" title="MFIX home page" target="_blank">MFIX home page</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>MM5</td>
      <td>MM5 is a limited-area, nonhydrostatic, terrain-following sigma-coordinate model designed to simulate or predict mesoscale atmospheric circulation.</td>
      <td><a href="http://www.mmm.ucar.edu/mm5/" title="MM5 Community Model Homepage" target="_blank">MM5 Community Model home page</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>NASTRAN</td>
      <td>NASTRAN Bulk data file format is an ASCII format that describes unstructured meshes. </td>
      <td><a href="http://www.mscsoftware.com/products/products_detail.cfm?PI=7">NASTRAN home page</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Nek5000</td>
      <td>Nek5000 is a file format developed for the Nek 5000 code at <a href="http://www.anl.gov/" title="ANL" target="_blank">Argonne National Laboratory</a>.</td>
      <td><a href="http://nek5000.mcs.anl.gov" title="Nek5000" target="_blank">Nek5000 home page</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>NetCDF</td>
      <td><p>NetCDF (network Common Data Form) is an interface for array-oriented data access and a library that provides an implementation of the interface. The netCDF library also defines a machine-independent format for representing scientific data. Together, the interface, library, and format support the creation, access, and sharing of scientific data.</p>
      <p>VisIt's NetCDF reader plugin supports conventions for the ADAPT, Lodi, and FVCOM simulation codes. If your NetCDF files were not generated with those codes then VisIt's basic NetCDF reader will attempt to expose all 1D, 2D, 3D arrays as variables that VisIt can plot. The basic reader does not permit you to specify coordinates for your mesh nor does it allow more than one time step in a file. If your file's variables are disabled in VisIt's plot menus then you may need to extend VisIt's NetCDF reader to support your code's conventions. </p></td>
      <td><p><a href="http://www.unidata.ucar.edu/software/netcdf/">NETCDF home page</a></p>
          <p><a href="http://www.unidata.ucar.edu/software/netcdf/guide.txn_toc.html">NETCDF User's Guide</a></p>
      </td>
    </tr>
	<tr>
      <td>OpenFOAM</td>
      <td>The OpenFOAM (Open Field Operation and Manipulation) CFD Toolbox can simulate anything from complex fluid flows involving chemical reactions, turbulence and heat transfer, to solid dynamics, electromagnetics and the pricing of financial options. OpenFOAM is freely available and open source, licensed under the <A 
href="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/licenses.html#GPL">GNU General Public License</A>. </td>
      <td><a href="http://www.opencfd.co.uk/openfoam/" title="OpenFOAM: The Open Source CFD Toolbox" target="_blank">OpenFOAM home page</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>PATRAN</td>
      <td>PATRAN neutral file, which is an ASCII file containing the definition for an unstructured mesh.</td>
      <td><a href="http://www.mscsoftware.com/products/products_detail.cfm?PI=6">PATRAN home page</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>PLOT3D</td>
      <td>Visualization application with accompanying file format developed at NASA Ames.</td>
      <td><a href="http://www.nas.nasa.gov/cgi-bin/software/start">Download PLOT3D</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Point3D</td>
      <td><p>Point3D is a simple ASCII text format for 3D particles that have 1 scalar variable. Point3D is not a widely used format but it can be useful for scripts or simple particle simulations that want an easy way to get particle data into VisIt. The file format consists of a comment line that includes the names of the coordinates and the variable name. The variable name is used in VisIt's plot menus. After the comment line, each subsequent line contains the (x,y,z) coordinates and variable value for a point. If you have more than 1 scalar variable to plot on your particles then consider using Silo or Xmdv file formats. </p>
      <p><em>Example file:</em><br />
      # x y z variablename<br />
      0 0 0 10<br />
      1 2 3 20<br />
      2 4 6 30</p>
      </td>
      <td>&nbsp;</td>
    </tr>
	<tr>
      <td>Protein Databank </td>
      <td>Protein Databank (PDB) files  contain molecular data describing the structures of biological macromolecules. </td>
      <td><a href="http://www.rcsb.org/pdb/Welcome.do" title="RCSB Protein Databank" target="_blank">RCSB Protein Databank</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>SAMRAI</td>
      <td>Format used by SAMRAI, which is a high-performance library for handling structured AMR data.</td>
      <td><a href="http://www.llnl.gov/CASC/SAMRAI/">SAMRAI home page</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Silo</td>
      <td>LLNL data file format for storing rectilinear, curvilinear, unstructured, or point meshes in 2D and 3D. Scalar, vector, and material data can be defined on meshes. Data can be broken up into different files (multi-block) to increase parallel performance.</td>
      <td><a href="https://wci.llnl.gov/codes/visit/3rd_party/silo020506.sh">Download Silo source code</a> <br />
          <br />
        Download Silo documentation [<a href="https://wci.llnl.gov/codes/visit/3rd_part/Silo.book.pdf">PDF</a>] </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Spheral</td>
      <td>Spheral++ is a steerable parallel environment for performing coupled hydrodynamical and gravitational numerical simulations.</td>
      <td><a href="http://spheral.sourceforge.net/">Spheral++ home page</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>STL</td>
      <td>STL, or stereo lithography format, is an ASCII or binary file used in manufacturing. It is a list of the triangular surfaces that describe a computer generated solid model. This is the standard input for most rapid prototyping machines.</td>
      <td><a href="http://www.sdsc.edu/tmf/Stl-specs/stl.html">STL file format description</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>TecPlot</td>
      <td>TecPlot is another popular visualization tool. VisIt can read the ASCII version of the TecPlot file format, though VisIt's reader does not handle all forms of the ASCII Tecplot file format. </td>
      <td><a href="http://www.tecplot.com/">TecPlot home page</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>VASP</td>
      <td>VAMP/VASP is a package for performing ab-initio quantum-mechanical molecular dynamics (MD) using pseudopotentials and a plane wave basis set.</td>
      <td><a href="http://cms.mpi.univie.ac.at/vasp/" title="VASP Group" target="_blank">VASP Group</a></td>
    </tr>
	<tr>
      <td>Vis5D</td>
      <td><A href="http://www.ssec.wisc.edu/~billh/vis5d.html">Vis5d</A> is  a free OpenGL-based volumetric visualization program for scientific datasets in 3+ dimensions. </td>
      <td><a href="http://vis5d.sourceforge.net/" title="Vis5D+ home page" target="_blank">Vis5D+ home page</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>VTK</td>
      <td>Visualization Toolkit (VTK) data file format. This is an ASCII-based file format that can store 2D and 3D meshes and data on those meshes.</td>
      <td><a href="http://public.kitware.com/VTK/pdf/file-formats.pdf">Download file format manual</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Wavefront OBJ </td>
      <td>Alias Wavefront's OBJ file format is useful for incorporating 3D models into your visualizations.</td>
      <td><a href="http://www.fileformat.info/format/wavefrontobj/">Wavefront OBJ file format description</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Xmdv</td>
      <td>File format used by XmdvTool, a public-domain software package for the interactive visual exploration of multivariate data sets.</td>
      <td><a href="http://davis.wpi.edu/~xmdv/fileformats.html">Xmdv file format description </a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>XDMF</td>
      <td>A standardized method to exchange scientific data between High Performance Computing codes and tools. It uses XML to store light data and HDF5 to store heavy data.</td>
      <td><a href="http://www.xdmf.org/index.php/Main_Page">XDMF home page</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>ZeusMP (HDF4) </td>
      <td>This database reader plugin reads HDF4 files from ZEUS-MP, which is a parallel addition to the ZEUS line of community application codes developed by the </A><a href="http://cosmos.ucsd.edu/" target="_blank">Laboratory for Computational Astrophysics</a>.</td>
      <td><p><a href="http://jhpc.ucsd.edu/ZEUS-2/" target="_blank">Zeus-MP 2.0 home page</a></p>
      <p><a href="http://cosmos.ucsd.edu/lca-www/software/lca_intro_zeusmp.html" target="_blank">Zeus-MP home page</a></p></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

</div>
</div>	
	  
	  ]]>
  </content>
</page>
