<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<page>
  <title><![CDATA[Release Notes for VisIt 2.10.2]]></title>
  <owner><![CDATA[Page Owner Name]]></owner>
  <IM>LLNL-WEB-687297</IM>
  <lastchanged><![CDATA[March 30, 2016]]></lastchanged>
  <template><![CDATA[l2]]></template> 
  <content>
    <![CDATA[
	
<link rel="stylesheet" href="content/css/mods.css" media="screen" />	

<div class="row">	
<div class="span9">

<ul class="nav nav-tabs">
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit">VisIt Home</a></li>
	<li class="active"><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/downloads">Downloads</a></li>
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/new">What's New</a></li>
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/screenshots">Screen Shots</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/gallery">Gallery</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/faqs">FAQs</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Welcome to VisIt's release notes page. This page describes the important
enhancements and bug-fixes that were added to this release.</p>

<h2>Bugs fixed in version 2.10.2</h2>
<ul>
  <li>A bug was fixed with the Silo database plugin where variables displayed in the plot menus would sometimes appear greyed out, making them unplottable.</li>
  <li>The <i>Restore session from sources</i> dialog was fixed to use the correct filter when specifying new sources.</li>
  <li>An engine crash was fixed that was caused by pick-by-global-id for datsets where some domains were empty.</li>
  <li>An engine crash was fixed that was caused by the SPH Resample Operator when receiving zero datasets.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Enhancements in version 2.10.2</h2>
<ul>
  <li>The host profiles for the ANL network were updated. Specifically, the host profiles for Eureka, Gadzooks and Tukey were removed and a host profile for Cooley was added.</li>
  <li>The VASP database plugin was enhanced to support the VASP XDATCAR format.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Changes for VisIt developers in version 2.10.2</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Build_visit was modified to build Python 2.7.11 and PIL 1.1.7 so that it can build VisIt on El Capitan.</li>
  <li>NVIDIA's cuda-memcheck is now an available memory debugger for VisIt.</li>
  <li>build_visit_BGQ was modified to include changes from Jens Henrik Goebbert for building on JUQUEEN.</li>
</ul>

<p>For any additional questions, send e-mail to <a href="mailto:visit-users@ornl.gov">VisIt Users</a>.</p>

</div>
</div>	
	  
	  ]]>
  </content>
</page>
