<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<page>
  <title><![CDATA[Release Notes for VisIt 2.7.2]]></title>
  <IM>LLNL-WEB-662419</IM>
  <owner><![CDATA[Page Owner Name]]></owner>
  <lastchanged><![CDATA[October 15, 2014]]></lastchanged>
  <template><![CDATA[l2]]></template> 
  <content>
    <![CDATA[
	
<link rel="stylesheet" href="content/css/mods.css" media="screen" />	

<div class="row">	
<div class="span9">

<ul class="nav nav-tabs">
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit">VisIt Home</a></li>
	<li class="active"><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/downloads">Downloads</a></li>
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/new">What's New</a></li>
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/screenshots">Screen Shots</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/gallery">Gallery</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/faqs">FAQs</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Welcome to VisIt's release notes page. This page describes the important bug-fixes that were made to this release.</p>

<h2>Configuration changes in version 2.7.2</h2>
<ul>
<li>A launch profile was added to the host profile for LLNL's <i>max</i> system for using the pvis partition.</li>
<li>A launch profile was added to the host profile for LLNL's <i>zin</i> system for using the pvis partition.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Bugs fixed in version 2.7.2</h2>
<ul>
<li>Creating database correlations on Windows from the CLI, when databases are opened using relative paths, has been fixed.</li>
<li>Session files with time varying data can be restored via the CLI with different sources and have their time sliders work correctly.</li>
<li>An engine crash on Windows was fixed when cmfe expressions were passed an invalid filename.</li>
<li>A bug was fixed where a plot got put in perpetual 'pending' state when NamedSelections' 'Automatially apply updated selections' was checked before the selection had been applied to a plot.</li>
<li>VisIt's Annotation window has been fixed so that it is once again possible to select axis tick marks that are both inside and outside of the 3D bounding box.</li>
<li>The silent uninstall option on Windows (/S from command-line) now works again.</li>
<li>A problem with material selection in plots from files containing a mix of multi-block and single-block meshes at the same dir-level and also containing standard block grouping was corrected (<a href="https://visitbugs.ornl.gov/issues/866">ticket #866</a>) .</li>
<li>The internallauncher was modified to correct a bug where the -N option was improperly set when using aprun to launch VisIt. Thanks Jean Favre for the fix.</li>
<li>The 2D and 3D zoom interactors once again unzoom the image when pressing the Ctrl key and the left mouse button.</li>
<li>Making movies with movie templates works again on Windows.</li>
<li>A small number of errors were fixed in the visit-install script. The "arl" and "asu" configurations are now supported with the "-c" option. The help text is now up-to-date and the configuration options are now listed in alphabetical order.</li>
<li>The ADIOS reader was fixed so that it now properly reads 3D uniform and rectilinear meshes.</li>
<li>A bug was fixed with a previous fix to the OnionPeel operater in VisIt 2.7.1 where it didn't properly handle the case where the seed cell was specified as a global cell number and material interface reconstruction was applied.</li>
<li>A bug with material indexing related to phony materials in the CaleHDF5 database reader was resolved.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Enhancements in version 2.7.2</h2>
<ul>
<li>The Cosmos++ reader has been extended so that accepts either combined or separate grid and data files. When static meshes are used, a single grid dump can now be provided, regardless of the number of data dumps.</li>
<li>Two new 2D quad mesh quality metrics (min_corner_area and min_sin_corner) were added.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Changes for VisIt developers in version 2.7.2</h2>
<ul>
<li>The build_visit script was modified to build MPICH 3.0.4 instead of 3.0.1 so that MPICH would build on Red Hat Enterprise Linux 5 systems.</li>
<li>The build_visit script was modified so that the MPICH library it builds is compatible with the Uintah library.</li>
<li>The build system was modified to add -DMPI_NO_CPPBIND and -DMPICH_SKIP_MPICXX to VISIT_PARALLEL_CFLAGS and VISIT_PARALLEL_CXXFLAGS so that the xdmf_writer sample programs could be built with more versions of MPI.</li> 
</ul>


<p>For any additional questions, send e-mail to <a href="mailto:visit-users@ornl.gov">VisIt Users</a>.</p>

</div>
</div>	
	  
	  ]]>
  </content>
</page>
