<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<page>
  <title><![CDATA[Release Notes for VisIt 3.1]]></title>
  <owner><![CDATA[Page Owner Name]]></owner>
  <IM>LLNL-WEB-796739</IM>
  <lastchanged><![CDATA[November 13, 2019]]></lastchanged>
  <template><![CDATA[l2]]></template> 
  <content>
    <![CDATA[
	
<link rel="stylesheet" href="content/css/mods.css" media="screen" />	

<div class="row">	
<div class="span9">

<ul class="nav nav-tabs">
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit">VisIt Home</a></li>
	<li class="active"><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/downloads">Downloads</a></li>
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/new">What's New</a></li>
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/screenshots">Screen Shots</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/gallery">Gallery</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/faqs">FAQs</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Welcome to VisIt's release notes page. This page describes the important
enhancements and bug-fixes that were added to this release.</p>

<h2>General features added in version 3.1</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Binary distributions have been added for CentOS 8 and Ubuntu 19.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Changes in GUI behavior in version 3.1</h2>
<ul>
  <li>The VCR play/reverse play buttons are now inactive when there are no active drawn plots.</li>
  <li>The following windows were restructured to reduce their height and allow for better usage on laptops: Pick, Preference, Host profiles configuration setup, Poincare operator, LCS operator, Limit Cycle operator and Integral Curve operator.</li>
</ul>

<h2>File format reader changes in version 3.1</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Corrected a bug with the VTK reader parsing .vtm files when the 'DataSet' tag doesn't have a 'file' attribute.</li>
  <li>An OpenPMD reader was added to VisIt. OpenPMD files are automatically recognized when the have the "pmd" or "opmd" extensions.</li>
  <li>The ADIOS2 reader was updated to use ADIOS2 2.5.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Changes to VisIt's plots in version 3.1</h2>
<ul>
  <li>The Pseudocolor plot can now render lines as tubes and ribbons and points as glyphs in mixed-topology unstructured grids and poly data.</li>
  <li>The Pseudocolor plot can now glyph points when <i>Draw objects as</i> is set to <i>Points</i>.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Changes to VisIt's expression language in version 3.1</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Added the <i>divide</i> expression to allow users to specify a divide by zero value and a tolerance for zero.</li>
  <li>Enhanced the <i>min</i> and <i>max</i> expressssions to support more than two input variables.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Changes to VisIt's picks and queries in version 3.1</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Corrected a bug where sometimes it wasn't possible to pick on a glyphed point lying near the dataset bounds.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Other bugs fixed in version 3.1</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Changing the opacity for a Pseudocolor plot no longer affects the glyph type of glyphed points.</li>
  <li>Corrected an issue with installing host profiles after deleting or moving the .visit folder while VisIt is running.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Build changes in version 3.1</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Modified build_visit to enable OpenSSL by default since Python depends on OpenSSL and Python is enabled by default.</li>
  <li>Corrected a bug in build_visit that prevented OSMesa and MesaGL from building from within a Git checkout.</li>
  <li>Added a patch to build_visit so that Qt builds on CentOS 8 and Ubuntu 19.</li>
  <li>Modified build_visit so that it would build Adios2 on Mac OS X.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Changes for VisIt developers in version 3.1</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Suppressed the Qt warning 'Empty filename passed to function'. Also added additional context information to the Qt log message if available.</li>
</ul>


<p>For any additional questions, send e-mail to <a href="mailto:visit-users@ornl.gov">VisIt Users</a>.</p>

</div>
</div>	
	  
	  ]]>
  </content>
</page>
