<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<page>
  <title><![CDATA[Release Notes for VisIt 3.1.1]]></title>
  <owner><![CDATA[Page Owner Name]]></owner>
  <IM>LLNL-WEB-780056</IM>
  <lastchanged><![CDATA[February 24, 2020]]></lastchanged>
  <template><![CDATA[l2]]></template> 
  <content>
    <![CDATA[
	
<link rel="stylesheet" href="content/css/mods.css" media="screen" />	

<div class="row">	
<div class="span9">

<ul class="nav nav-tabs">
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit">VisIt Home</a></li>
	<li class="active"><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/downloads">Downloads</a></li>
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/new">What's New</a></li>
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/screenshots">Screen Shots</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/gallery">Gallery</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/faqs">FAQs</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Welcome to VisIt's release notes page. This page describes the important
enhancements and bug-fixes that were added to this release.</p>

<h2>Bugs fixed in version 3.1.1</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Corrected a bug where certain types of mili datasets would cause unexpected crashes.</li>
  <li>Corrected a bug where the Data level comparison wizard would always enter zero for the simulation cycle.</li>
  <li>Corrected a bug where zone pick highlights were incorrect after transforms were applied.</li>
  <li>Corrected a bug summing mesh_quality/volume in a sub-material setting.</li>
  <li>Corrected a bug where VisIt crashes on start-up on some Windows systems when the system OpenGL version is too old. VisIt now determines the OpenGL version during the installation process and uses Mesa3D as a drop-in replacement if needed, with a warning on the installer pages to notify the user that the graphics cards / drivers should be updated.</li>
  <li>Corrected a bug importing remote profiles from a Windows system.</li>
  <li>Corrected a bug performing QueryOverTime with plots involving operator-created expressions.</li>
  <li>Corrected a bug where VisIt would only display a black window when displaying on a Windows system running the XWin-32 X Server.</li>
  <li>Corrected a bug with external surfaces not display with Pseudocolor Plots when the centering is changed from original centering.</li>
  <li>Corrected a bug where makemili_driver was not properly installed, making it unusable.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Enhancements in version 3.1.1</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Updated the mfem library to version 4.0.</li>
  <li>Added host profiles for Leibniz Supercomputing Centre.</li>
  <li>Enhanced the FFP database plugin and enhanced to use libstripack when it is available, either installed in VisIt's lib dir or the path specified via the VISIT_FFP_STRIPACK_PATH environment variable.</li>
  <li>Removed the host profile for Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory's rzuseq system.</li>
  <li>Removed the use of the rzgw gateway from all the Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory's RZ host profiles.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Changes for VisIt developers in version 3.1.1</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Updated build_visit to work on macOS 10.14.</li>
  <li>Enhanced build_visit to download the visit source code and third party libraries from GitHub instead of NERSC."</li>
  <li>Updated build_visit to allow the user to disable the building of Sphinx. To disable building Sphinx specify "--no-sphinx".</li>
  <li>Enhanced build_visit to also package VisIt into a tar file after building it so that VisIt is ready to install.</li>
  <li>Enhanced build_visit to also build the VisIt manuals when building VisIt.</li>
  <li>Enhanced build_visit to add checksums for the VisIt source tar file when writing a unified file. It assumes that the tar file containing the VisIt source file is in the current directory. If any errors are encountered and it can't add the checksums a warning is printed.</li>
</ul>

<p>For any additional questions, send e-mail to <a href="mailto:visit-users@ornl.gov">VisIt Users</a>.</p>

</div>
</div>	
	  
	  ]]>
  </content>
</page>
