<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<page>
  <title><![CDATA[Release Notes for VisIt 2.3.2]]></title>
  <owner><![CDATA[Page Owner Name]]></owner>
  <lastchanged><![CDATA[March 26, 2013]]></lastchanged>
  <template><![CDATA[l2]]></template> 
  <content>
    <![CDATA[
	
<link rel="stylesheet" href="content/css/mods.css" media="screen" />	

<div class="row">	
<div class="span9">

<ul class="nav nav-tabs">
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit">VisIt Home</a></li>
	<li class="active"><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/downloads">Downloads</a></li>
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/new">What's New</a></li>
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/screenshots">Screen Shots</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/gallery">Gallery</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/faqs">FAQs</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Welcome to VisIt's release notes page. This page describes the important
bug-fixes that were made to this release.</p>

<h2>Bugs fixed in version 2.3.2</h2>
<ul>
<li>VisIt no longer hangs when displaying from a Linux computer to a MacOS X computer over X11.</li>
<li>If you have a running session with multiple windows, and you restore a session with one window, VisIt no longer unexpectedly exits.</li>
<li>Curve plots created via the <i>operators/Lineout</i> variable menu in a plot variable menu are now handled properly when the variable name contains spaces.</li>
<li>When you using cross-mesh field evaluations, VisIt now correctly issues a warning when accessing invalid time slices.</li>
<li>The <i>VisIt_RectilinearMesh_setBaseIndex</i> function in Libsim now behave properly.</li>
<li>A bug was corrected in the Enzo reader that caused it to fail sometimes on Windows.</li>
<li>A bug was corrected in the PF3D reader where the data was not being properly decompressed for one of the compression schemes.</li>
<li>The PF3D reader was modified so that it doesn't crash when changing timesteps and some of the subfiles are not readable.</li>
<li>Repeatedly passing character array variables with different string values to Libsim was broken. In the old scheme, arrays were assumed to contain the same contents and conversion to C-style strings under the covers would only happen once.</li>
<li>A bug was corrected in the principal_tensor, principal_deviatoric_tensor and tensor_maximum_shear expressions, where a cutoff used to prevent numeric overflows and underflows was too argressive causing the expressions to calculate incorrect values for small values.</li>
<li>VisIt again honors vis window size information stored in session files and config files for the case where there is a single vis window.</li>
<li>The InverseGhostZone operator is now more agressive about invalidating data limits so the limits shown in the legend will reflect the values in the ghost data only.</li>
<li>The Xdmf reader now correctly reports simulation time.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Enhancements in version 2.3.2</h2>
<ul>
<li>The VCell reader from UCHC was added.</li>
<li>The Enzo reader was enhanced to support the multi-resolution control operator.</li>
<li>Libsim was enhanced to have a <i>VisItGetSockets</i> function that returns the socket file descriptors used by the <i>VisItDetectInput</i> function. This new function lets you obtain the socket descriptors in case you want to add them to your own <i>select</i>-based event loop.</li>
<li>VisIt can now read NumPy array files (via the BOV reader). Supported data types are byte, short, 32-bit integeres, float and double.
</li><li>Serial and parallel host profiles were added for LLNL's coastal, rzalastor and rzzeus systems.</li>
</ul>

</div>
</div>	
	  
	  ]]>
  </content>
</page>
