<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<page>
  <title><![CDATA[Release Notes for VisIt 2.13.1]]></title>
  <owner><![CDATA[Page Owner Name]]></owner>
  <IM>LLNL-WEB-748158</IM>
  <lastchanged><![CDATA[March 26, 2018]]></lastchanged>
  <template><![CDATA[l2]]></template> 
  <content>
    <![CDATA[
	
<link rel="stylesheet" href="content/css/mods.css" media="screen" />	

<div class="row">	
<div class="span9">

<ul class="nav nav-tabs">
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit">VisIt Home</a></li>
	<li class="active"><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/downloads">Downloads</a></li>
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/new">What's New</a></li>
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/screenshots">Screen Shots</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/gallery">Gallery</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/faqs">FAQs</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Welcome to VisIt's release notes page. This page describes the important
enhancements and bug-fixes that were added to this release.</p>

<h2>Bugs fixed in version 2.13.1</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Query over time was modified to store the results in double precision instead of single precision.</li>
  <li>The VTK Reader was modified to ensure material scalars in multi-block datasets are read correctly.</li>
  <li>VisIt will now display an error message on Windows if VISITSSH is defined, but does not point to an executable, and if a parallel engine is requested but mpiexec.exe cannot be found.</li>
  <li>A bug was corrected with the ScatterPlot Setup Wizard populating the variable menus from a previous database.</li>
  <li>A bug was corrected with the Threshold operator thresholding point meshes.</li>
  <li>A bug was corrected where VisIt would crash when performing a lineout when -dump was specified on the command line.</li>
  <li>VisIt's viewer was enhanced to address a performance issue where it unnecessarily created text labels that would likely not be used unless displaying a ParallelCoordinates plot. For Subset plots with large numbers of domains, this caused the viewer to use many gigabytes of memory even when scalable rendering was used.</li>
  <li>A bug was corrected where VisIt would crash performing a time-query when the Curve plot was disabled. An error message will now be issued, and the query will not be performed.</li>
  <li>A bug was corrected with build_visit with the building of Qt with -no-openssl specified on the command line on Fedora systems.</li>
  <li>The exporting of data to Silo files was modified to always set the MetadataIsTimeVarying attribute to ensure VisIt handles exported data correctly in cases where the metadata is time-varying. This will probably result in a minimal performance degradation in cases where its not necessary.</li>
  <li>A bug was corrected where VisIt would crash opening certain NetCDF-4 files on Windows.</li>
  <li>A bug was corrected where VisIt would crash when the number of nodes or zones or tuples times the number of components exceeds INT_MAX in a single block.<li>
  <li>A bug was corrected with the Save Window compression options so that only those options appropriate to the currently selected format are enabled for selection.</li>
  <li>A bug was corrected with the active window selector in the main window so that it now displays more than a single digit if necessary.</li>
  <li>A bug was corrected with running Python filters in parallel on Windows.</li>
  <li>A bug was corrected where VisIt would hang on start up when running on a Windows VM.</li>
  <li>A bug was corrected with Python filters failing on Windows 8, 10.</li>
  <li>A bug was corrected where the VisIt metadata server would crash when it encounterd a Silo file with a multimesh that was invalid, such as when the number of blocks specified was zero.</li>
  <li>VisIt was modified so that crash session files created by any running VisIt process are correctly ignored by any additional VisIt processes that are launched.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Enhancements in version 2.13.1</h2>
<ul>
  <li>The SPCTH reader was enhanced to process a list of MTMD files as one MTMD file.</li>
  <li>The <i>parallel interactive pdebug</i> host profile for the LLNL <i>cab</i> machine was modified to handle job launching changes on the machine.</li>
  <li>The <i>parallel viz</i> host profile for the LANL <i>trinity</i> machine was modified to handle job launching changes on the machine.</li>
  <li>The Pixie reader was enhanced to read datasets with more than INT_MAX nodes or zones.</li>
  <li>The default compression method for saving windows was changed from PackBits to None.</li>
  <li>The performance of VisIt was improved when populating file lists from directories with large numbers of entries.<li>
  <li>VisIt now saves crash session files for a specific VisIt process. The user can choose which crash session file to restore if multiple ones exist.<li>
  <li>VisIt has been enhanced to select between chaos 5 and toss 3 executables on LLNL systems based on the machine name instead of the environment variable SYS_TYPE. Some users didn't have the SYS_TYPE environment variable set causing the previous logic to fail in some instances.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Changes for VisIt developers in version 2.13.1</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Build_visit was modified to pass the zlib directory information to the configure command for hdf5 when -zlib was specified on the command line.</li>
  <li>Build_visit was modified to patch pyside2 to remove the conditional collecting of the Multimedia, WebEngineWidget, and WebKit modules.</li>
  <li>A bug was corrected with the creation of a QWT symbolic link on OSX.</li>
  <li>A bug was corrected with the naming of the PySide2 and Shiboken2 libraries on OSX.</li>
  <li>Build_visit was modified to build Qt in silent mode by default. Additionally, build_visit was modified to allow specifying <i>--no-qt-silent</i> on the command line to disable building Qt in silent mode.</li>
  <li>The location where the default variables are set in the viewer was changed so that plot plugins can override the default values in their CustomizeBehavior method.</li>
  <li>Numpy was upgraded from version 1.11.2 to 1.14.1.</li>
  <li>The Python CLI was enhanced to make it possible to the control visibility of annotation objects during their creation with an additional argument in the CreateAnnotationObject() method.</li>
  <li><i>Make package</i> was modified so that it no longer includes any directories named <i>icons</i>. Previously, this resulted in a couple of invalid symbolic links being added to the distribution file.</li>
</ul>

<p>For any additional questions, send e-mail to <a href="mailto:visit-users@ornl.gov">VisIt Users</a>.</p>

</div>
</div>	
	  
	  ]]>
  </content>
</page>
