<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<page>
  <title><![CDATA[Release Notes for VisIt 3.0.2]]></title>
  <owner><![CDATA[Page Owner Name]]></owner>
  <IM>LLNL-WEB-XXXXXX</IM>
  <lastchanged><![CDATA[September 9, 2019]]></lastchanged>
  <template><![CDATA[l2]]></template> 
  <content>
    <![CDATA[
	
<link rel="stylesheet" href="content/css/mods.css" media="screen" />	

<div class="row">	
<div class="span9">

<ul class="nav nav-tabs">
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit">VisIt Home</a></li>
	<li class="active"><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/downloads">Downloads</a></li>
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/new">What's New</a></li>
  	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/screenshots">Screen Shots</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/gallery">Gallery</a></li>
	<li><a href="simulation/computer-codes/visit/faqs">FAQs</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Welcome to VisIt's release notes page. This page describes the important
enhancements and bug-fixes that were added to this release.</p>

<h2>Bugs fixed in version 3.0.2</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Corrected a bug where VisIt would crash when attempting to use python expressions with other expressions as inputs.</li>
  <li>Fixed launch failure on Windows when 8dot3name (shortnames) is disabled on the system.</li>
  <li>Fixed issue with the mili plugin not handling integers in scientific notation.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Enhancements in version 3.0.2</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Host profiles were added for the Oak Ridge National Laboratory's Summit system.</li>
  <li>Tables in the GUI doc that ran off the edge of the page have been converted to definition lists.</li>
  <li>Modified the batch launching at NERSC to work on Cori after the major operating system upgrade."</li>
  <li>Openssl was added to the list of required libraries in build_visit.</li>
  <li>Added the turbo color table.</li>
  <li>XYZ Writer repalces '?' with UNKNOWN_ATOMIC_ELEMENT and now warns user if dataset is not effectively point-centered.</li>
  <li>Xdmf reader now supports time-varying grid count via top-level
      &lt;Information Name="TimeVaryingMetaData" Value="True"/&gt; node in the xdmf file.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Changes for VisIt developers in version 3.0.2</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Updated masonry to build adios2 for OSX.</li>
  <li>Fixed building plugins against a VisIt install for OSX.</li>
  <li>Fixed xmledit failure due to missing QT cocoa plugin.</li>
  <li>Fixed the libxml2 image not found error when loading the uintah database.</li>
  <li>PySide was removed from build_visit until we get a newer version working with VisIt.</li>
</ul>

<p>For any additional questions, send e-mail to <a href="mailto:visit-users@ornl.gov">VisIt Users</a>.</p>

</div>
</div>	
	  
	  ]]>
  </content>
</page>
